<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Gabriel Lopez</title><link>http://localhost:1313/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Gabriel Lopez</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Test</title><link>http://localhost:1313/posts/test/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/test/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="test-page">Test Page&lt;/h2></description></item><item><title>The Eternalblue Story</title><link>http://localhost:1313/posts/eternal-blue/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/eternal-blue/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The story of the eternalblue vulnerability is quite an interesting one as it comes back to the ever-recurring issue of government spying and whether or not the ends justify the means when it comes to government spying for the sake of protection.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="background-info">Background Info&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Before getting into the events of what happened surrounding the discovery of the eternalblue vulnerability it is important to know what this vulnerability is in the first place. Eternalblue was a vulnerability in the file-sharing service SMB in various Windows operating systems. These operating systems included Windows Vista all the way to Windows Server 2016. This was done by using corroded packets sent to the service which allowed for remote code execution. According to NIST, this was designated with a CVS score of 8.8&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>. To put this score into perspective usually anything ranging from a 6-1 is considered minor, 7 is somewhat a concern, and 8-10 is a major problem.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Pando: The Trembling Giant</title><link>http://localhost:1313/posts/pando/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/pando/</guid><description>&lt;p>Was made aware of a tree a few days ago by a friend. It is called Pando. It is apparently the world&amp;rsquo;s largest tree.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here is a picture of it here:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="http://localhost:1313/nature/pando/regPando.jpg" alt="reg pando">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It a tree that is located in Utah in the Fishlake National Forest and wasn&amp;rsquo;t realy recognized as a tree until 1976 when it rediscovered in a sense by two &lt;a href="https://www.friendsofpando.org/faq1pando101/" title="Pando FAQ">ecologists&lt;/a>. It&amp;rsquo;s pretty cool to look at when you see in the Fall too, when its leaves change to a bright almost yellow-orange color.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>