<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Gabriel Lopez</title><link>https://gabealopez.github.io/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Gabriel Lopez</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://gabealopez.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Heavens Gate</title><link>https://gabealopez.github.io/posts/heavens-gate/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabealopez.github.io/posts/heavens-gate/</guid><description>When Microsoft introduced 64-bit Windows, backward compatibility for 32-bit applications remained essential. This compatibility layer, called WOW64 (Windows-On-Windows 64-bit), allowed older software to function seamlessly. Underneath this compatibility abstraction, however, an opportunity emerged for attackers.
Security solutions frequently focused their defenses around 32-bit behaviors, neglecting less commonly exploited 64-bit operations. Heaven’s Gate was born from this oversight, enabling threat actors to break free from WOW64’s restrictions and execute unmonitored 64-bit code.</description></item><item><title>Black Hat Zig</title><link>https://gabealopez.github.io/posts/black-hat-zig/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabealopez.github.io/posts/black-hat-zig/</guid><description>This project provides many malware techniques implementation using Zig since I&amp;rsquo;m a huge fan of it. You can use this repo to weaponize Zig. Black-Hat-Zig is continuously updating to make sure it contains as more content as it could. It will be perfect if you want to create a PR for this project.
Black Hat Zig This is a really neat project I found that&amp;rsquo;s using a new modern programming language called zig.</description></item><item><title>Automation Mindset - Technical Details</title><link>https://gabealopez.github.io/posts/automation-mindset-technical-details/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabealopez.github.io/posts/automation-mindset-technical-details/</guid><description>Foreword As a brief disclaimer, I want to make it clear that I do not consider myself an expert or advanced scripter, and that is completely acceptable. It is important to understand that not all code is perfect on the first attempt, and the code I will be discussing here is no exception.
This was my first serious attempt at automating a task within a real enterprise environment, so the code is far from optimal.</description></item><item><title>Automation Mindset - A How To</title><link>https://gabealopez.github.io/posts/automation-mindset-a-how-to/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabealopez.github.io/posts/automation-mindset-a-how-to/</guid><description>Introduction Welcome! Welcome! Traveler, I see you’ve come to hear the tale of automation’s greatness. Excellent choice. Shall we begin?
So… what is automation? I know, I know-you didn’t come here for a history lesson. Neither did I. But a little context helps, so don’t click away just yet. You hear me?
Anyway, in today’s digital world, automation means using technology to handle repetitive tasks—automatically. Instead of manually sending emails, moving files, or copying data, software does it for you.</description></item><item><title>The History of BonziBuddy</title><link>https://gabealopez.github.io/posts/bonzibuddy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabealopez.github.io/posts/bonzibuddy/</guid><description>Intro If you are like many you might be asking what the heck BonziBuddy is. Well to put it simply it was one of the virtual assistants that was created back in the day of Windows XP to help out with everyday office tasks. Many virtual assistants like BonziBuddy were created at the time since many users did not like current default implementation from Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s virtual assistant named clippy. Because of this many people created many differing virtual assistants that had extended upon what clippy could do.</description></item><item><title>The Birth of Computer Viruses: Origins and Evolution</title><link>https://gabealopez.github.io/posts/the-first-virus/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabealopez.github.io/posts/the-first-virus/</guid><description>Self-Replicating Automata Now the idea of having a program replicate itself was, actually, not new. The first real theory of a self-replicating program starts in the 1940s with a mathematician named John von Neumann. His designs called for a universal separator, which builds the machine from a copier which replicated a machine&amp;rsquo;s description. The separation he called for allowed for mutations, enabling the new automata to evolve much like real organisms1.</description></item><item><title>The Origin of Hacking and the Evolution of it</title><link>https://gabealopez.github.io/posts/the-start-of-hacking/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabealopez.github.io/posts/the-start-of-hacking/</guid><description>Introduction Originally hacking was never really attributed to the way the Hollywood portrays it today. In it&amp;rsquo;s more original state, hacking was making something happen that wasn&amp;rsquo;t intended to do. This meaning that to hack it to make a contraption do something that it was not intended to do or supposed to do in the first place.
For example, a drill is intended to be used to, well, drill holes and drill screws into walls.</description></item><item><title>The Eternalblue Story</title><link>https://gabealopez.github.io/posts/eternal-blue/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabealopez.github.io/posts/eternal-blue/</guid><description>Introduction The story of the eternalblue vulnerability is quite an interesting one as it comes back to the ever-recurring issue of government spying and whether or not the ends justify the means when it comes to government spying for the sake of protection.
Background Info Before getting into the events of what happened surrounding the discovery of the eternalblue vulnerability it is important to know what this vulnerability is in the first place.</description></item><item><title>Pando: The Trembling Giant</title><link>https://gabealopez.github.io/posts/pando/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabealopez.github.io/posts/pando/</guid><description>Was made aware of a tree a few days ago by a friend. It is called Pando. It is apparently the world&amp;rsquo;s largest tree.
Here is a picture of it here:
It a tree that is located in Utah in the Fishlake National Forest and wasn&amp;rsquo;t realy recognized as a tree until 1976 when it rediscovered in a sense by two ecologists. It&amp;rsquo;s pretty cool to look at when you see in the Fall too, when its leaves change to a bright almost yellow-orange color.</description></item></channel></rss>