<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Projects on Gabriel Lopez</title><link>http://localhost:1313/projects/</link><description>Recent content in Projects on Gabriel Lopez</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>HTB CTFs</title><link>http://localhost:1313/projects/cybersecurity/ctf-writeups/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/cybersecurity/ctf-writeups/</guid><description>Disclaimer There are CTFs here that I have done and have written on a repo I have on GITHUB, however future CTFs are going to be posted here. There will headers for ones that are marked to go to my github repo
247 CTFs From GITHUB Compare-The-Pair
Secured-Session
Trusted-Client
HTB CTFS From GITHUB Web Challenges ApacheBlaze
Insomnia
PDFy
ProxyAsAService
RenderQuest
jscalc
Boxes BoardLight
Mailing
PermX</description></item><item><title>LARK Project</title><link>http://localhost:1313/projects/intro-to-unix/lark-project/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/intro-to-unix/lark-project/</guid><description>Github Link LARK Project Link
Explanation This project, as the description shows, was to teach new user to Unix/Linux systems the commands that they would be using in their day to day life. Many of these commands included &amp;rsquo;ls&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;cd&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;cat&amp;rsquo;, etc. However the interesting spin me and my team members had was that we designed as a puzzle game with a story added with it.
The puzzles would get progressively get harder and harder, trying to get the player to build upon what they had learned in the past.</description></item><item><title>Salaries (WIP)</title><link>http://localhost:1313/projects/data-analysis/salaries/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/data-analysis/salaries/</guid><description>Cybersecurity Salaries Data Analysis The following is some data analysis I did on a dataset for cybersecurity salaries throughout the world. I wanted to find some interesting trends in the data that I had downloaded here on Kaggle
Overall there were some interesting trends within the data and others that made sense. One of these observations was in salaries over time where USD salaries had increased over time. Along with this observation, I had went to ask the question of wether or not location mattered when it came to USD salaries.</description></item><item><title>Kernel Maze Game</title><link>http://localhost:1313/projects/operating-systems/project-explaination/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/operating-systems/project-explaination/</guid><description>Description This is an explaination and showcase of a program I made in my OS class that more or less produces a maze in the terminal from the kernel level</description></item><item><title>HTB Pentesting Checklist/Playbook</title><link>http://localhost:1313/projects/cybersecurity/htb-pentesting-checklist-and-playbook/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/cybersecurity/htb-pentesting-checklist-and-playbook/</guid><description>Enumeration NOTE: These steps are more general Ofc. Playbook gets more detailed later
Run nmap scan with following command: nmap -p- -sVC -vv &amp;lt;IP Addr&amp;gt; -oA enum/nmap Search on google for each port that is found on hacktricks for pentesting them Look for unusual ports that are not usually opened NOTE: Focus on ports other than port 80/443 first as 80/443 will take a longer time to enumerate
Overall for the ports I like to use https://book.</description></item><item><title>Red Team Tools</title><link>http://localhost:1313/projects/cybersecurity/list-of-red-team-tools/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/cybersecurity/list-of-red-team-tools/</guid><description>Hi there, here is a list of red team tools I have used in CTFs:
Directory Bruteforcing Feroxbuster - Recursive bruteforcing FUFF - Very flexible fuzzing tool Web Proxies Burpsuite - Most popular web proxy OWASP ZAP - Opensource alternative to Burpsuite Inspect Element - The ghetto web proxy Website Finger-Printing Tools Whatweb - A command line tool to help identify the backend and frontend of a website Wappalyzer - Works similarly to Whatweb but is a browser extension instead SQL Injection SQLmap - A nice tool to help automate discovering and exploiting SQL injections Cryptography CyberChef - Website based tool to help analyze and decrypt any encrypted text SMB Tools Crackmapexec - Post exploitation tool when you have found credentials on an SMB server Also a very helpful enumeration tool SMB Client - A local linux tool to use SMB shares Enum4linux - Automation tool to enumeration tool NOTE: In actual pentests it is advised to not really use this tool as it creates too much noise for the client NetExec - Another post exploitation tool for when you have credentials for an SMB server Active Directory Blood Hound - A nice enumeration tool when you have an initial shell on a windows machine This tools helps to produce a json file to import into the Blood Hound website so you can find a connection from your current user account to a domain admin</description></item></channel></rss>