<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>History on Gabriel Lopez</title><link>http://localhost:1313/tags/history/</link><description>Recent content in History on Gabriel Lopez</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/history/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Birth of Computer Viruses: Origins and Evolution</title><link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-first-virus/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-first-virus/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="background">Background&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The idea of a self-replicating program was not a foreign concept at the time of the world&amp;rsquo;s first computer virus called Creeper&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="the-worlds-first-computer-virus">The World&amp;rsquo;s First Computer Virus&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The world&amp;rsquo;s first well known computer virus was called Creeper and it was developed by a BBN programmer, Bob Thomas&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>. Thomas initially created this virus as an experiment to test the idea of a self-replicating program, or worm. When Thomas had released it for testing he did not realize the extent to which his program would spread and found out quickly as his virus had quickly corrupted the DEC PDP-10 mainframe. After being corrupted these computers would go on to display a message saying &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m the creeper, catch me if you can!&amp;rdquo;. Now is not really considered a malicious virus as the virus did not destroy or steal data and it only displayed a simple message.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Origin of Hacking and the Evolution of it</title><link>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-start-of-hacking/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/the-start-of-hacking/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Originally hacking was never really attributed to the way the Hollywood portrays it today. In it&amp;rsquo;s more original state, hacking was making something happen that wasn&amp;rsquo;t intended to do. This meaning that to hack it to make a contraption do something that it was not intended to do or supposed to do in the first place.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For example, a drill is intended to be used to, well, drill holes and drill screws into walls. Now what if someone took that same drill and used it instead as a way to spin a top fast. Now this wasn&amp;rsquo;t the intended way of using the drill but you made this drill become the best top spinner in the world. Now in the case with computers, certain computers are designed to do a task, like holding data and restricting access to that data. But in the case of hacking, an attacker would make that computer show data to themselves that he does not have access to.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Eternalblue Story</title><link>http://localhost:1313/posts/eternal-blue/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/eternal-blue/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The story of the eternalblue vulnerability is quite an interesting one as it comes back to the ever-recurring issue of government spying and whether or not the ends justify the means when it comes to government spying for the sake of protection.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="background-info">Background Info&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Before getting into the events of what happened surrounding the discovery of the eternalblue vulnerability it is important to know what this vulnerability is in the first place. Eternalblue was a vulnerability in the file-sharing service SMB in various Windows operating systems. These operating systems included Windows Vista all the way to Windows Server 2016. This was done by using corroded packets sent to the service which allowed for remote code execution. According to NIST, this was designated with a CVS score of 8.8&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>. To put this score into perspective usually anything ranging from a 6-1 is considered minor, 7 is somewhat a concern, and 8-10 is a major problem.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>