<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cybersecurity on Gabriel Lopez</title><link>https://gabealopez.github.io/tags/cybersecurity/</link><description>Recent content in Cybersecurity on Gabriel Lopez</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://gabealopez.github.io/tags/cybersecurity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Automation Mindset - A How To</title><link>https://gabealopez.github.io/posts/automation-mindset-a-how-to/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabealopez.github.io/posts/automation-mindset-a-how-to/</guid><description>Introduction Welcome! Welcome! Traveler I see you wish to hear about the greatness of automation! That&amp;rsquo;s good news. Well? Shall we begin? What is automation? I know I know you didn&amp;rsquo;t come here for a history lesson. Neither did I but this is to give you context to everything I will say. So don&amp;rsquo;t click away just yet. You hear me!?
Anyway automation, in today’s digital workflows, means using technology to handle repetitive tasks automatically.</description></item><item><title>Resources</title><link>https://gabealopez.github.io/projects/cybersecurity/resources/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabealopez.github.io/projects/cybersecurity/resources/</guid><description>Red Team Pentesting Malware Development General Evading Antivirus Detection in C (with Dahvid Schloss) - John Hammond
Description: An interesting talk John Hammond had with Dahvid Schloss for his insight on Malware development
Youtube - Crow
Description: A good channel I found to learn about some good hands-on info about creating malware
0xPat Blog
Description: A good blog I found about creating malware and some techniques to avoid detection
thecyberidiots - Dahvid Schloss Company&amp;rsquo;s blog - &amp;ldquo;Fun with PowerShell – Executing commands with DNS requests&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>HTB CTFs</title><link>https://gabealopez.github.io/projects/cybersecurity/ctf-writeups/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabealopez.github.io/projects/cybersecurity/ctf-writeups/</guid><description>Disclaimer There are CTFs here that I have done and have written on a repo I have on GITHUB, however future CTFs are going to be posted here. There will headers for ones that are marked to go to my github repo
247 CTFs From GITHUB Compare-The-Pair
Secured-Session
Trusted-Client
HTB CTFS From GITHUB Web Challenges ApacheBlaze
Insomnia
PDFy
ProxyAsAService
RenderQuest
jscalc
Boxes BoardLight
Mailing
PermX</description></item><item><title>The History of BonziBuddy</title><link>https://gabealopez.github.io/posts/bonzibuddy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabealopez.github.io/posts/bonzibuddy/</guid><description>Intro If you are like many you might be asking what the heck BonziBuddy is. Well to put it simply it was one of the virtual assistants that was created back in the day of Windows XP to help out with everyday office tasks. Many virtual assistants like BonziBuddy were created at the time since many users did not like current default implementation from Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s virtual assistant named clippy. Because of this many people created many differing virtual assistants that had extended upon what clippy could do.</description></item><item><title>Salaries (WIP)</title><link>https://gabealopez.github.io/projects/data-analysis/salaries/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabealopez.github.io/projects/data-analysis/salaries/</guid><description>Cybersecurity Salaries Data Analysis The following is some data analysis I did on a dataset for cybersecurity salaries throughout the world. I wanted to find some interesting trends in the data that I had downloaded here on Kaggle
Overall there were some interesting trends within the data and others that made sense. One of these observations was in salaries over time where USD salaries had increased over time. Along with this observation, I had went to ask the question of wether or not location mattered when it came to USD salaries.</description></item><item><title>The Birth of Computer Viruses: Origins and Evolution</title><link>https://gabealopez.github.io/posts/the-first-virus/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabealopez.github.io/posts/the-first-virus/</guid><description>Self-Replicating Automata Now the idea of having a program replicate itself was, actually, not new. The first real theory of a self-replicating program starts in the 1940s with a mathematician named John von Neumann. His designs called for a universal separator, which builds the machine from a copier which replicated a machine&amp;rsquo;s description. The separation he called for allowed for mutations, enabling the new automata to evolve much like real organisms1.</description></item><item><title>The Origin of Hacking and the Evolution of it</title><link>https://gabealopez.github.io/posts/the-start-of-hacking/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabealopez.github.io/posts/the-start-of-hacking/</guid><description>Introduction Originally hacking was never really attributed to the way the Hollywood portrays it today. In it&amp;rsquo;s more original state, hacking was making something happen that wasn&amp;rsquo;t intended to do. This meaning that to hack it to make a contraption do something that it was not intended to do or supposed to do in the first place.
For example, a drill is intended to be used to, well, drill holes and drill screws into walls.</description></item><item><title>The Eternalblue Story</title><link>https://gabealopez.github.io/posts/eternal-blue/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabealopez.github.io/posts/eternal-blue/</guid><description>Introduction The story of the eternalblue vulnerability is quite an interesting one as it comes back to the ever-recurring issue of government spying and whether or not the ends justify the means when it comes to government spying for the sake of protection.
Background Info Before getting into the events of what happened surrounding the discovery of the eternalblue vulnerability it is important to know what this vulnerability is in the first place.</description></item><item><title>HTB Pentesting Checklist/Playbook</title><link>https://gabealopez.github.io/projects/cybersecurity/htb-pentesting-checklist-and-playbook/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabealopez.github.io/projects/cybersecurity/htb-pentesting-checklist-and-playbook/</guid><description>Enumeration NOTE: These steps are more general Ofc. Playbook gets more detailed later
Run nmap scan with following command: nmap -p- -sVC -vv &amp;lt;IP Addr&amp;gt; -oA enum/nmap Search on google for each port that is found on hacktricks for pentesting them Look for unusual ports that are not usually opened NOTE: Focus on ports other than port 80/443 first as 80/443 will take a longer time to enumerate
Overall for the ports I like to use https://book.</description></item><item><title>Red Team Tools</title><link>https://gabealopez.github.io/projects/cybersecurity/list-of-red-team-tools/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://gabealopez.github.io/projects/cybersecurity/list-of-red-team-tools/</guid><description>Hi there, here is a list of red team tools I have used in CTFs:
Directory Bruteforcing Feroxbuster - Recursive bruteforcing FUFF - Very flexible fuzzing tool Web Proxies Burpsuite - Most popular web proxy OWASP ZAP - Opensource alternative to Burpsuite Inspect Element - The ghetto web proxy Website Finger-Printing Tools Whatweb - A command line tool to help identify the backend and frontend of a website Wappalyzer - Works similarly to Whatweb but is a browser extension instead SQL Injection SQLmap - A nice tool to help automate discovering and exploiting SQL injections Cryptography CyberChef - Website based tool to help analyze and decrypt any encrypted text SMB Tools Crackmapexec - Post exploitation tool when you have found credentials on an SMB server Also a very helpful enumeration tool SMB Client - A local linux tool to use SMB shares Enum4linux - Automation tool to enumeration tool NOTE: In actual pentests it is advised to not really use this tool as it creates too much noise for the client NetExec - Another post exploitation tool for when you have credentials for an SMB server Active Directory Blood Hound - A nice enumeration tool when you have an initial shell on a windows machine This tools helps to produce a json file to import into the Blood Hound website so you can find a connection from your current user account to a domain admin</description></item></channel></rss>